-这么巧？来看看吗？  -我来看看他们的手艺
Hi! dub...
-喂  等等我  -一起吧
Hi! wait for me, let's go
（大上海男女理发）
SHANGHAI BARBER SHOP
恭喜
Thanks.
-开心仔  先来亲一口  -先来亲一口
-Kiss me, Happy. -Kiss me.
好  下次逐个轮流亲  好吗？
Okay.
-开张大吉  谁要第一个理发？  -我
-Who likes to go first? -Me.
-好吧  你们自己解决啊  -我先
-Let me try first. -Okay, settle among yourselves.
-我先  我先来的  -你干什么啊？
-Me first. -Me first.
转过来吧
Turn around.
-真好看  -好美啊
Wow, you're beautiful.
连花都特别臭
It stinks!
老板  以后想找一只苍蝇来看都难了
Sir, all the flies here will be extinct.
为什么？
Why?
这么多人拍掌  当然绝种
Killing flies will be our pastime.
看他什么时候倒闭
Chill, it won't be long.
理个发收费几百块
Over a hundred dollars for a cut!
又不会刮胡子
They don't shave,
又不会按摩
they don't massage,
又不会采耳
and they don't even do ear candling!
撩下
You tell me,
都不知道有多过瘾呢
how many idiots
光顾他的全都是人头猪脑
would go there to do their hair. They would be foolish!
真好看
It's classy!
先亲一个
Let me give you a kiss.
-塌下来了  -讨厌  再剪一次
It's ruined! Do it again.
好
Okay.
（大上海男女理发）
SHANGHAI BARBER SHOP
先生  到了
We're here, sir.
你马上后退30厘米
Back up five feet at once!
这就是长乐街13号了
This is 30 Cheong Lok Street.
总之我说退就退
Just do as I tell you.
不多不少刚好30厘米
Reverse by exactly five feet!
神经病
Jeez.
有没有搞错？
That was crazy!
这样也行？真是太离谱
Wow, that's incredible!
-不用了  没关系  请收起来吧  -来  这怎么行？
-Here. -No, it's okay. You may have it back.
-你可真是世外高人呢  -是吧？
You are a fortune teller, right?
你在哪里摆档口？怎么称呼？
Where is your stall? What's your name?
有空拜托你替小弟指点迷津
l need your sage advice.
赖布衣第18代传人赖布甸是也
I'm Puddin Lai, the 18th generation of Lai Prophets.
有缘就有缘  没缘就完蛋
Fate will decide if we meet again.
若是有缘  下次我再指点你两句
If it does, I'll advise you
-我帮你消灾解难吧  -谢谢
to keep out from misfortune again.
大师  为什么你会自身难保呢？
Sir, why didn't you predict that?
因为你而漏露天机啊
l unveiled heaven's secrets for you,
-我又帮你挡了一个小劫  -真的？
so I took the hit for your sake.
-看啊  -谢谢大师
-Really? -Of course. Thank you, master.
-是赖大师  -谢谢  赖大师
-Master Lai. -Master Lai,
-走吧  -谢谢
thank you.
妖气冲天
l sense
难怪会这样
something alarming.
这个方位会出现劫难
And it's coming from this direction.
好吧  让我叉
I'm going to charge.
-我剪  -叉
-I'm going to cut. -I charge.
-出来帮忙  -剪
-Come out and help! -Charge.
-叉  -我剪
I cut.
停手  还要剪是吧？
Hold it, what are you cutting?
算了  我不玩了
Okay, count me out.
叉  叉你老妈！
"Charge." Charge your ass!
-对不起  开心！  -你想怎么修？
-Excuse me. Happy!
-你说呢？喂！  -开心
-Whatever you say. Hey!
你的头发怎么搞的？  是用了什么发胶？
Look at your hair. What gel did you use?
别理了  隔壁理发店那个老鬼非常凶  你知道吗？
Forget about that, but the barber next door is so evil!
不过幸好我躲过了这一劫
You know that? Luckily l got through unscathed.
今天我连过两劫
Today, l averted two misfortunes.
算我命好  糟了！
Consider me lucky. Oh, no!
-什么事？还有第三劫吗？  -什么糟了？
-What is it? -What's wrong?
-九号  你别理他  -喂  你别说话
-The ninth. -Stop talking.
糟了  真的有第三劫
Oh, no, there is a third misfortune!
不过幸好不是我  是龙眼仔
Luckily, I'm not getting it, but it Big Eye is. What?
恭喜
Congratulations!
开张大吉  生意兴隆
May your new shop grow and thrive,
财源广进  手艺超凡
and let your fine craft earn you big.
恭喜
Congratulations!
对不起  祝贺错了人
Sorry, I was mistaken.
不是这里吧？
I got the wrong shop.
不
No.
这里也一样  到处都一样
But it still applies here, just like it does everywhere.
总之生意兴隆  财源广进  一…
Anyway, may your new shop grow and thrive...
恭喜
Congratulations.
真是刀法如神
You're pretty skillful.
-臭小子  别走  耍我？  -别走
Kid, come back here! Did you play with me?
我没耍你
No, I didn't.
-不是耍我  那就是认真的？  -我不是认真的
-Yes, you did it on purpose! -I didn't mean it.
那就是玩我了？
Yes, you did!
-也把他的眉毛给剃了  -好！
Shave his eyebrows!
-射他  -射他
-Spray. -Spray.
-快点过来啊  -过来啊
-Come here, Big Eye. -Come here, Big Eye.
-过来啊  射他  -射他
Come back! Spray them!
射那个老头！
Spray that old man!
-射他！  -住手！
-Spray them! -Stop it!
-射他！  -小姐！
-Miss! -What now?
-够了！  -那是她爸爸啊！
En...
是她爸爸
Dad.
-爸爸  -我不是  他才是
-Dad. -I'm not your dad, he is.
爸爸  怎么搞成这样？
Dad, what happened to you?
你为什么跟人家斗气？
Why did you pick a fight with them?
你干爹变成一眉道人了
Look what they did to his brow.
你爸爸英雄本色
Your dad is not
誓不两立  誓不低头
going down without a fight
义胆雄心
because he's
岂有此理  书剑恩仇
got a heart of steel. See!
我有仇必报
I'm going to get you!
-好棒  -好棒
Bravo!
老板好棒  刀法如神
That was awesome!
真厉害
Bravo!
真棒
怕了吧？
Go to hell.
臭小子  看什么？
What are you turds looking at?
看什么？阿英快进去
What are you looking at? Ying, go in!
改天再找你们算账
I'm not through with you yet.
没戏了
Nothing to see!
还看什么？回去！
Go inside.
怎么了？进回去吧！
-Let's go back inside! -Let's go back.
-开心哥啊  -别理他了！
Don't bother them!
真漂亮
So pure
新鲜
and fresh.
Fresh.
柳黛眉、西施鼻、贵妃额
I can tell by her eyebrows, nose, and forehead
是旺夫益子的面相
that she's a walking lucky charm!
阿英  我娶定你了
Ying, I'll marry you for sure!
-英  我对不起你  英…  -喂！
-Ying, I'm so sorry. -Hey.
我过来向你道歉了
Let me apologize on their behalf.
一定倒霉
It's bad.
想不到这么倒霉
Worse than I predicted.
今年我的桃花运旺盛  她是我的了
I'm going to find some love this year!
喂！
Hey!
-你看吧  把我们的关系都搞砸了  -我？
-See? Look what you did to us. -Me?
你闯下这么大的祸  应该由你亲自进去处理的
You made this mess, so you go clean it up.
还不赶快进去道歉？
Go and apologize right now!
-你们知道我吃什么药吗？  -什么药？
-You know what my instinct tells me? -What?
千万不“药”啊！
Never go in!
你快点进去摆平它
You mucked up, so you fix it!
-就算赔钱也要赔  -赔钱？
-Even if you have to pay for it. -Pay for it?
-当然了  -喂
-Yes! -Hey.
放心吧  也许阿英会因你而感动呢
Who knows, Ying would be touched if you're sincere.
感动？
Touched?
-是啊  -那也对哦？
-Sure. -Yes.
-这个大祸不可能要你们负责的  -是啊
So I can't pass the buck to you.
-没道理由我们来负责  -乖乖去吧
-I'll have to shoulder it myself. -We'll help you.
麻烦你快点解决它就对了
Okay, hurry along now.
记住  耶稣会罩着你的
Remember, Jesus is with you.
菩萨会保佑你的
So are the Bodhisattvas.
菩萨保佑
Bodhisattvas, help me.
（大上海男女理发）
各位好
Hi, guys.
伯父  是这样的…
Sir, let me explain.
这么快就结束营业了？
Wow, you're closing early?
不是
No...
我胡说
I didn't mean that.
乌鸦嘴
Slip of the tongue.
伯父  我专诚来向你道歉的
Sir, I've come to apologize to you.
-伯父  你…  -爸爸
-Sir. -Dad.
爸爸  你别这样
Dad, please don't.
你爸爸  我19年来
For over 19 years in business,
客人的一条眉毛都从没剃错过
I never shaved an eyebrow by accident
直到今天为止
until this day.
看看
Watch.
剃你两条眉毛  算是赔偿剃错我一条眉毛
I'm going to shave both your eyebrows to make up for one of mine.
什么？两条？
What, both of them?
伯父
Sir,
如果嫌剃眉毛麻烦的话
instead of eyebrows,
剃胡子吧
please shave my beard.
如果剃胡子都嫌麻烦的话
Or if that's not okay with you,
那赔钱吧
I'll compensate in cash.
谢谢
-Thanks.
赔多少？
-How much?
100元
One hundred dollars.
500元？每人赔500元
Five hundred dollars! One hundred dollars each, okay?
少一点你就完蛋了  快点
That sounds good enough. Now, pay up!
别给少了
It's going to be fine.
爸爸  别这样！
Dad, no...
-走吧  -你…
-Run for it! -You
走了
guys!
我帮你画回去吧
I'll fix it with makeup.
糟了  好像歪了
Oh, no. It looks distorted.
不是啊
No,
画得比真的还漂亮
you drew it great.
你手艺超凡
You did really fine.
这么久还没出来？  这次应该凶多吉少了
What's keeping him? He's out of luck now.
随时有可能当了香港最新鲜的太监
They could've castrated him by now.
他也真是的  有勇无谋
He has guts but no wit.
怎么去和女子搭讪？
-He's not good enough to flirt with girls.
-太不自量力了  -真可惜
-Too bad about that.
改天再帮你画吧  对不起
I'll draw it up next time. Sorry.
难道他成功？
-He did it?
我不信
-I can't believe my eyes.
-再见  -再见
Bye Bye
扶住我
Take me...
撑住
-Be careful. -Hey.
有点不同
He looks different.
好像不太对劲  是什么呢？
Yes, something's different. What is it?
高了？
I'm much taller.
-高了  -高了
-Yes. Taller. -Yes. Taller.
现在我们来数单数
Now. we counting...
左、右、左、右
Letf, right....
很好
Good.
-女儿  -再来
Again.
半决赛当晚  替你梳个八爪鱼发髻好吗？
How about this hairstyle for the semifinals?
多两次
More twins
这个呢？奥米加发型  好吗？
Would you like this omega style?
好
Yes!
那就决定这个了
It's this one then.
快点去替妈妈梳吧  去吧
Go do that hair for Mommy.
女儿  不要跳了
Ying, take a rest.
快来吃东西吧
Have some refreshments.
上海婆  你别来打扰她
Do you mind, Ms. Shanghai?
还没跳够30分钟
Her 30 minutes aren't up yet.
什么？你想让女儿跳到死去吗？
What, you want her to die exhausted?
我说先休息一下
l say, take a rest.
现在  你不想女儿拿下冠军吗？
Don't you want her to win?
有一百万奖金
It's one million dollars, you know.
还有可以钓个金龟婿
She would also be able to marry a rich guy.
爸爸  将来我嫁的人
Dad, what matters most is that my future husband
最重要是我喜欢他  他也喜欢我就行了
will love me, and I'll love him back, that's all.
为什么一定要嫁有钱人呢？
He doesn't have to be rich.
是啊  见钱眼开  当女儿是摇钱树吗？
That's right! Don't think you can milk money out of our daughter.
妇人之见
That's what women think.
（大上海理发）
SHANGHAI BARBER SHOP
（《红楼梦》）
DREAM OF THE RED CHAMBER
-请坐  -好的
-Have a seat. -Thanks.
坐
Sir, please.
臭豆腐
Stinky tofu!
Who wants some stinky tofu?
-喂  怎么回事？  -臭豆腐
What's up?
来  大家一起来吃
Come on, let's eat together!
伯父  你喜欢这玩意儿
Sir, I'm sure you like this.
-试试臭豆腐  好啊  -你也吃吃看
You too.
有辣椒酱
Have some chili sauce.
不用客气
Help yourself.
吃一块吧
Here you go.
这块是最臭的
This is the smelliest.
-好好吃  -伯父  我今天是专诚来向你道歉的
Sir, I've come here just to apologize
还有洗头  跟你学习学习
and get my hair shampooed.
-很美味  -好吗？
Good smell
-慢慢吃  -吃多几块吧
Enjoy.
不要客气
Help yourself.
阿英  试试看
-Ying, try one.
谢谢  我不吃的
-No, thanks. I don't eat this.
你不喜欢吃？
You don't like it?
不是要洗头吗？这边
Do you want to shampoo? Right this way.
怎么不是她？她…
Why isn't she...
伯父怎么这么给面子  要你自己来？
It's so nice of you to do the honors.
-阿福  -是的？
-Fook! -Yes?
-招呼他  -好
-It's yours. -Okay.
-洗头？  -喂  你的手
-Shampoo? -Your hand!
冲水
Rinse.
那边
That way.
阿英
Ying.
走吧
Go on.
伯父
Sir!
送个招财老虎给你
l present you this fortune tiger.
那以后财源就会滚滚而来了
It will bring you money.
我现在生意不好吗？
Is my business not doing well now?
生意当然好
Your business is surely brisk.
赚钱哪有嫌多的  对吧？
But money is never too much, right?
这个招财老虎放哪里好呢？
Where shall we place this fortune tiger?
这个方位好啊  这个方位…
This is a good area.
-这个方位真旺  -小伙子
Good for money.
这位子是旺财  不是旺色
This place is good for money, not good for sex.
伯父  你真幽默  伯父
You do have a good sense of humor.
其实我这次过来的目的是向你道歉
In fact, I've come to apologize
顺便来洗头的
and have my hair shampooed as well.
洗头是那边  付钱才是这边
Shampoo over there, and payment here.
洗头吗？
Shampoo?
画眉而已
To have my eyebrow drawn.
画眉？
Your eyebrow?
伯父
Sir,
阿英  这些花很漂亮  我想…
Ying, these flowers are so beautiful, I'd like to...
对了  我最喜欢这些花了
Yes, I like these flowers.
那就送给伯父吧
Especially for you, sir.
-阿英  这个招财老虎…  -你不是说要洗头吗？
-Ying, this-- -Don't you want a shampoo?
去洗头吧
Go.
别乱碰我的东西
Don't touch my stuff.
阿英  我去洗头了
I'll have a shampoo first.
阿英  现在画吧
Ying, draw it.
-你是不是在附近工作？  -是
-Is your place of work nearby? -Yes.
-刚刚下班？  -是
-Just off work? -Yes.
当然是下班啊  难道这么晚还上班吗？
Why would anyone be at work this late?
对了  你怎么不去大草那里洗头呢？
Why don't you go to Grassy Salon next door?
不要提大草了  伯父
Don't mention that, sir.
那间店都乱来的  不断乱抓乱扯你的头发
They are reckless over there. They would pull and pluck your hair.
-洗完头会不见几撮头发的  -是吗？
Their shampoo would cause your hair to fall off.
-伯父  真的是这样  -真的？
-Is that true? -Really.
-很多人也是这么说的  -对吧？
-A lot of people said that, right? -Yes.
乱说
Bullshit.
你朋友说话还蛮夸张的
Your friend seems to be exaggerating.
他啊  经常都是这样的
He is always like that,
十句有九句都是骗人的
spewing bullshit most of the time.
什么？
What?
不过这样  伯父  他这次说的完全正确
But this time, he tells the whole truth.
我知道
l know.
洗头不要乱动  还小吗？
Don't move about like a child, okay?
你们这样出卖好友  好像没什么义气
You shouldn't talk behind your friend's back like that.
不是没有义气  伯父  我们是在说出事实
It's not that I'm not being nice, but those are the facts.
大草  名字够难听了
Grassy, what a lousy name.
论理发技术  更是比不上上海理发店
Their skills are no match to what this Shanghai master can do.
-你说是吗？  -当然是啊
-Right? -Yes.
伯父  以后你看见我那个发型师朋友
Sir, when you see our hairstylist friend,
你问他大草好还是上海好
ask him which is better, Grassy or Shanghai?
他一定会说上海比较好
He will surely say Shanghai.
闭嘴！
Shut up!
没义气！猪朋狗友！
You pigs! Rats!
原来你在这里  那就对了
So, there you are.
抚心自问
Now, be honest.
是不是上海比大草好？
Is Shanghai better than Grassy?
-你说是不是？  -你敢说不是？
-Is it? -How dare you say no!
不是…
No!
才怪  伯父
l mean yes.
-伯父  是不是啊？我都说了  -伯父  是不是啊？
You see! Sir, l was right.
坐下吧
Sit down.
坐
Sit
-跟你坦白说  -好吧
Tell me....
看你们三个这么会说话
Well, since you three are so appreciative,
我亲自替你们吹个漂亮发型吧
l myself will do your hair.
-好啊  伯父  -好啊
-How nice of you, sir. -How nice of you, sir.
-谢谢阿英  -谢谢阿英
-Thank you, Ying. -Thank you, Ying.
不准进去！
Hey, don't go in.
你啊  你狼心狗肺
You animal!
-你啊  你忘恩负义  -说你啊
-You ingrate! -Like he said.
给我滚！
Get lost!
你冷静点  当我们是客人进去洗个头行吗？
Cool it! Just let us in as customers. All right?
就是啊  别这么认真
Don't take it so seriously.
我们刚才在里面是开玩笑而已
You saw what happened, we were joking.
-是的  开玩笑而已  别那么认真  -开什么玩笑？
-Yes, we're just fooling around. -Why are you fooling around?
说…
We're just...
是大小便不分的中分头！
What a hairstyle!
进去吧
Get inside.
进去吧  土包子
You look like a country bumpkin.
喂  大上海那家伙是不是在骗你？
Did the Shanghai barber trick you?
为什么连阿英的影子都看不见？
I don't see a single trace of Ying.
我给了他100元  他高兴到快哭了
l gave the barber 100 bucks, he was so grateful.
喂  会不会是骗…
Did he cheat us?
绝对不会  因为我昨晚梦见桃花流水
No! l dreamed of peach blossoms floating on the river.
今天我一定走桃花…
l am sure I'll get a girl this time.
是阿英
Ying.
-阿英  这么巧？  -这么巧？
-Ying! What a coincidence. -What a coincidence.
-是大上海的伙计…  -不是  这是缘分
-It's the Shanghai barber-- -No, fate brought us together.
阿英  这些是你的亲戚吗？
Ying, are they your relatives?
不是  是我的学生
No, they are my students.
趁着放暑假教他们游泳
l teach them swimming during holidays.
-我们来热身吧  -那就好了
-Let's warm up. -Good.
来  过来
Come here.
不如也收我们做徒弟吧
Please teach us.
-好的  一起玩吧  -好
Let's have fun together. Good.
一、二、三
One, two, three...
二、二、三
Two, three...
-看  他们全做错了  -三、二
-Look, they are doing it all wrong. -Three, two...
-当然  他们只会直盯盯地看着老师  -三  对了  是这样
-They are just staring at the teacher. -Three, that's it.
-都不知道他们想怎样  -四、二
-Who knows what they are thinking. -Four, two...
-四、二、三  -喂  我懂你们两个臭小子在想什么
-l know what you are thinking. -Five, two, three.
-你又懂？  -五
You do?
你们想嗒阿英
You want to dab Ying.
嗒？那是什么意思？
"Dab"? What does that mean?
嗒的意思就是问候
Dab means say hello to her.
-你们说是不是？  -没错  对
-Is that right? -Yes.
谢了  “嗒”这个字  我记住了
Thanks. "Dab." l got it.
-他们又骗老师了  -是啊
-He's fooling the teacher again. -Yes.
各位同学
Class...
我们现在开始做吸气训练  好吗？
Let's practice your breathing techniques now. Okay?
-好  -好
-Yes! -Yes!
小心点  对  是这样
Becafule
-老师  我不会换气  -对了
-Miss, l don't know how to breathe. -There you go.
好吧  我下来教你吧
All right, I'll teach you.
-我去帮你教他  -我去帮你教他
-Let me do it for you. -Let me do it for you.
小朋友
Hi, kid.
男子汉大丈夫  连吸气也不会？
How are you going to be a man if you can't draw breath?
对啊  很简单而已
It's so simple.
我吸一口气就可以潜水半个小时
l can hold my breath and submerge for an hour--
-所以我…  -喂  赖先生
No! Just half an hour for one breath,
有没有搞错？半个小时而已？
Why?
我吸一口气  就能轻松地由九龙塘游到香港
l can swim across the harbor.
-骗人  -要骗小孩吗？
-Liar. -Don't make a fool out of the kids.
-对啊  -别只是用嘴巴说  要去做啊
Yes, you're all talk and no action.
没错  你敢不敢做？
Right. Can you do it?
做就做啊  谁怕谁？
Why not? Go ahead.
-比什么啊？  -别只是靠嘴巴说
-Let's test our endurance.
比比看谁先淹死  谁最先被抬上来
-Let's see who will die of exhaustion.
-我们来比赛  -好！
-We will have a race. -Okay!
-各位小朋友  你们当证人好吗？  -好不好？
Children, you will be our judges. Okay?
-好  -好
-Okay! -Okay!
阿英  你来当评判
Ying, you will be the referee.
好吧  各位同学看着  开始
All right, let us watch them.
老师  我想下去看看他们有没有使诈
Miss, I would like to see if they will break the rules.
好  你下去吧
Right, go ahead.
老师  他们喷的泡泡很漂亮
They breathe out beautiful bubbles.
是吗？
Really?
-老师  -怎么了？
-Miss -What?
他们在说脏话
They speak vulgar language.
怎么会呢？在水里面怎么听见？
How could you hear them underwater?
他们张开大嘴
They were growling at each other.
-老师  -怎么了？
-Miss. -What?
他们很口渴
They must be thirsty.
怎么可能？
Why?
他们不停地在喝水
They took in so much water.
真的吗？
Really?
-老师  -怎么了？
-Miss. -What?
他们好像我家的金鱼一样
They look like fish in my aquarium.
是怎么样？
Like what?
双眼都凸出来了
Their eyes stick out.
怎么样？没事吧？
How are they? Are they okay?
麦香鸡  不要按
Don't press, children!
几位要点什么喝吗？
What would you like to drink?
-不要了  -千万不要  别这样对我
-Oh, no thank you. -Oh, no thank you.
阿英
Ying!
你很喜欢教小孩子游泳吗？
You like conducting swimming lessons for kids?
是  我很喜欢小孩子
Yes, I like children a lot,
趁着暑假就教他们游泳  自己也可以锻炼
and it's summer vacation now. I can keep fit as I train them.
下个月香港小姐比赛…
The Miss Hong Kong contest is next month.
没事了
Nothing
-香港小姐？  -香港小姐？
-Miss Hong Kong. -Miss Hong Kong.
我接到通知
l got in the semifinals.
我入围了
I am in
-这下好了  我是做保险经纪的  -对了  是18号啊
How nice! l am an insurance agent,
我可以替你买份保险  保证你一定赢
l can help you to make the right decision.
简直是有王者之风
You got the swag like a queen.
还是让我来摸一下
Let me have a touch, just to be sure...
你这只手都不知道占了多少人便宜
I wonder how many times you've used the same old trick.
到现在还用这一招？
-To take advantage of someone? -Hey.
要不要让阿英给你看她的裸体？
Are you asking her to bare all for you?
你竟然这样诋毁我？
Shame on you.
谁叫你想占便宜
Don't get any ideas!
这么卑鄙也做得出来
He has a dirty mind.
本性难移  不要怪他
He's like that.
他为人是这样的
He's always like that.
阿英  我叫纪浩仁
Ying, I'm Kei Ho Yan.
我叫陈开心
I'm Chan Hoi Sum.
-又名龙眼仔  -记住我
-You can call me Big Eye. -Remember me.
我学时装设计的
I'm studying fashion design.
我学发型设计的
I'll be a hairstylist.
我可以帮你设计一款晚礼服
l can design an evening gown for you.
我马上想到了一个很适合你的发型
l can create the perfect hairstyle for you.
我可以帮你…
Let me help you.
喂  老板
Sir, here's five bucks for you.
给你五元
Give you 5
等一下千万不要把账单递给我
Don't bring me the bill.
行  没问题
Sure, no problem.
-相信我吧  我帮你设计一个新发型  -别说了
-Trust me, I'll create a new hairstyle. -Will you stop talking?
-保证你满意  -差不多了  走吧？结账！
-We're almost finished. Bill please. -Coming.
来了
-Here! -Thanks.
-这里  我付  -谢谢先生
This way
-让我付吧  我请她喝茶  -让我付账吧
Let me pay the bill.
拿来吧
Allow me.
-喂！  -不要抢了
No, let me pay.
给我啊
-不要抢  -你们真客气都说我请了
You're too modest. I told you I'll pay.
别这么客气
-You're too kind. -Let me pay.
让我来  我请客
Stop snatching it.
-别抢了  -你拿得这么紧我怎么给他们？
Hey, don't grip so tight. How am I going to give them?
让我来吧
It's my turn.
喂  还不付钱？
Why don't you pay?
你很少抢赢的
You seldom pay.
现在怎么办？
What now?
那就是我付钱啊  还能怎样？
It means l pay!
你的问题怎么这么奇怪？
Why ask a stupid question?
要不要还五块钱给你？
Do l have to pay you back?
不用找零了
Keep the change!
-Yes, keep the change. -Thank you!
谢谢  先生
Thank you, sir.
（大上海理发）
SHANGHAI BARBER SHOP
阿英
Ying.
伯父  送给你的
It's for you, sir.
下次不要送花了  折算现金吧
Next time, no flowers. Just cash.
伯父  我想了一个晚上
Sir, l thought about it the whole night
我终于决定…
and decided...
冷静一点
Hold your horses!
送给你的
To give you this.
这适合我用吗？
Is it suitable for me?
是
Yes.
这把刀全世界只有两个人使用
Only two men in the world are fit to use it.
一个就是史泰龙
One is Stallone,
一个就是你了  伯父
and the other is you.
是吗？
Really?
屎什么窿？
What Stallone?
史泰龙
Stallone,
兰博
Rambo!
-刀法如神  -是吗？
Great swordsmanship!
这把刀好锋利
It's sharp.
他说史泰龙、兰博都是用它的
He said Rambo used it.
好锋利啊  真是厉害
It's so sharp, it's terrific!
碰一下都不得了了
One touch and you're finished!
你看见了吧？
You see that?
真是好锋利
It's a great knife.
是锋利  不过就对你不利了
It's so sharp, it cuts into your wallet.
我知道
l know.
不过我只有200元
l have got 200 dollars only.
剃眉毛都要500元了
Even one eyebrow is worth 500 dollars.
还有一张支票  不过还没填数额
l have got a blank check.
行了  我会填的
I'll fill in there.
真的是看见都心凉了
It sends chills to your back.
连心都凉了？我先走了
It does. Got to go.
傻小子
Silly boy.
这样的话  还凉不凉？
Not so chilly now.
女儿
-My girl. -Yes.
难道你喜欢那三个男孩子吗？
Do you like those three young men?
不是  我们才见过几次面而已
No, we just met a few times.
对啊
Right.
难道我们的阿英  会喜欢这么普通的人吗？
Our daughter won't like such ordinary men.
爸爸  你别胡说！
Dad, please!
你不喜欢人家那还请人家回来吃饭？
Then, why did you invite them to dinner?
不是  是利用他们而已
To manipulate them.
他们三个人会利用游泳和洗头
Those three would flirt with Ying
来追求阿英
with different excuses.
我也会利用他们三只公狗
I'll make use of the three dogs
去帮阿英参加竞选
to help Ying in the beauty contest.
说什么？利用三只公狗？
What, three dogs?
你把我女儿当什么了？
What do you take your daughter for?
没有
No.
让他们狗咬狗骨
I would let the dogs
互相监视啊  老婆
watch each other.
来了
There they are.
-你们好  -阿英
-Hi, Ying.
你好
-Ying.
-来了？  -伯父
-You're here! -Sir!
-私人珍藏的  -适合你饮用  伯父
-This is a collector's edition. -It's especially for you, sir.
是吗？真的吗？
Oh, really.
-小小意思  伯父  -这瓶是最贵的
Just a small favor, sir. This is the most expensive one.
-小小礼物  不成敬意  -交给阿英吧
-It's just a little gift. -Give it to Ying.
-阿英  摆好它  -小心放好
-Take care of it. -Ying, take care of it.
进来坐
Come in and sit down.
-上海婆  可以开饭  -伯父…
-Honey, time for dinner. -Sir.
-房子好漂亮  -伯父  我…
It's a beautiful house. Sir, l...
还不错
Very well
伯母
Ma'am.
我就是赖布甸了
My name is Puddin Lai.
阿英经常提起的那个
Ying must always mention me.
是的  他说你做发型设计的  是吗？
Yes, you are the hairstylist, right!
最近生意好吗？
How's business lately?
普通啦
Not too bad.
好香  伯母  你的手艺真的一流
Ma'am, it smells good. You're an excellent cook!
你做的山竹牛肉  真的是色香味俱全
Your minced beef looks, smells, and tastes good!
这是狮子头  不要在这里碍手碍脚
It's fried meatball. Now, get out of my way.
到外面聊天吧
Sit outside.
-伯母  -伯母
-Ma'am! -Ma'am!
-我来帮你  -你懂什么狮子头？出去！
-Let me give you a hand. -You don't know fried meatballs! Out!
-伯母  你继续  -伯母  我来帮你
-Let me help you.
-走吧  -不用了
-Let's go.
-喝茶吧  -谢谢阿英
-Have some tea. -Thank you, Ying.
对了  阿赖
By the way, Puddin,
听说你对风水和掌相很有研究？
how did you excel in feng shui, and palmistry?
是的  我们当经纪的时间多
I'm an insurance agent, l study those
研究一下而已
in my spare time.
伯父  我帮你看看手相
Sir, let me read your palm.
厚而多肉  好掌
It's thick and fleshy.
这是好掌
Nice.
所以你家山有福  女儿又长得美
You're blessed, that's why you have a pretty daughter.
真的是百年难得一见
It's not every day I get to see this palm.
伯父  我想跟阿英进房间
Sir, can I follow Ying to her room?
我是想看看她的服装  顺便帮她弄造型
I would like to see her clothes and how she dress up.
阿英  进房间吧
Ying, let's go in.
不要急  改天才弄吧
No hurry, some other day.
我试过很多种洗发精
l tried many brands of shampoo.
不知道哪一种适合我
I can't decide the right one for my hair.
-不如你帮我看看吧  -好啊
-Can you help me? -Sure.
我的头发很干燥
My hair tends to be dry.
对  这些头发都开叉了
You are right, you see, they split.
-你看看这里都开叉了  -是啊
-Quite a lot of splits. -Yes.
叉  叉死你吧
Split on your dead body.
死？谁死？
Who is dead?
你这种是死里逃生命
Oh, your palm marks escape from death.
大富大贵的意思
It means you're going to be rich.
蛮不错的
Not bad.
是
Yes.
没事的
It's all right.
-我每个星期帮你修剪一下就行了  -修  修你娘
-I'll trim it every week, that'd be great. -Cut the crap.
来吧  吃饭吧
Dinner time.
-阿英  我跟你坐吧？  -阿英  我跟你坐吧？
May l sit with you, Ying?
对不起  你坐那边
Sorry, move over.
-伯父  坐吧  -来吧  坐这里
That's my seat. Sit over here.
伯母
Ma'am.
-怎么煮这么多菜？  -吃吧  不用客气
-So much food. -Feel at home. Get started.
-干杯  -干杯
-Cheers. -Cheers.
妈妈
Mom.
他们呢  经常都想来嗒你的
They have longed to dab you for some time.
爸爸  他们也是想嗒你很久了
Dad, they've wanted to dab you too.
是的  很早就想来嗒你的酒了
Yes, we've wanted to dab your wine.
-干杯  -干杯
Cheers.
谢谢你们今晚嗒我全家  干杯
Thank you for coming to dab our family.
阿英  你在说什么？
Ying, watch your words!
-应该的  -应该的
-Our pleasure! -Our pleasure!
-喝吧  -上海婆  这么高兴  来喝一杯
-Cheers. -Honey, you're so happy, why don't you drink?
我？
-Me?
-对啊  妈  喝吧  这么开心  -喝吧
-Yes, everyone's happy.
-好吧  -喝吧
-Okay. -Okay.
-伯母真棒  -今天这么高兴  多喝一杯吧
Ma'am, have another glass.
-不行  我不会喝酒的  -喝多一杯吧
-l can't drink much. -Just one more glass.
-没关系的  喝吧  -一杯
-Doesn't matter, have another. -Just one more.
就喝一杯吧
Drink it up.
那好吧  既然大家这么高兴
We're all very happy today.
我把它当凉茶来喝吧
I'll just drink it up.
-好棒！  -妈妈真棒！
伯母好棒
Nice one!
-伯母好酒量！  -你们慢慢吃  我去看看鱼好了没有
-You're such a good drinker. -Go ahead while l go check the fish.
-伯父  你真是好客  -随便吃
-Sir, you are hospitable. -Make yourselves at home.
爸爸…
Dad.
-妈妈  -伯母
-Mom? -Ma'am.
要不要叫救护车？
Want to call an ambulance?
-快点抬她进房吧  -不用这么夸张
Let's carry her altogether.
-快点抬她进去吧  -要用力哦  她很重的
She is too heavy.
小心啊
B.C
你们真没用
You are useless.
快搬开吧  我快窒息了
Remove her, l can't breathe.
喝多了
Hey, you've drunk too much.
-他喝多了  伯父  -吐回去  没关系
-Sir, he took too much. -Spit it back out.
-放点酱油进去  -吐回去吧
-Add some sauce. -Spit it out.
没多了  来
We're almost out. Let's see who gets it.
-来  再猜拳！  -来！
Bring it on!
万宝路啊  万宝路
Marlboro...
-柠檬茶啊  柠檬茶  -万宝路啊  万宝路
Lemon tea...
-关冷气啊  关冷气  -关冷气
No air-con...
-你输了  -你输了
-You lost. -You lost.
-你输了  你一定要喝  -猜多一次吧
-The loser must drink. -Drink it up.
-一次  -不行
-One more time. -No way!
-一次  -好  再多给他一次机会
Okay. One more chance for you.
来
Come on
关冷气啊  关冷气
No air-con...
-喝吧  -你得喝了
-Drink up. -You must drink up!
喝吧
Drink up.
-喝吧  还等什么？  -喝吧  快点啦
-What are you waiting for? -Just drink!
不喝！
No drink!
愿赌服输  喝吧
You lost, you should drink.
对了  喝吧
Yes, do it.
把它喝了吧
-Drink. -Do it.
-喝吧  -傻小子
Silly boy.
喝了它吧
Drink it up.
快点  老顽固  来  抓住他
Don't be stubborn! Come, hold him.
-嘴巴张开  -来吧  放松一点
Open your mouth, relax.
差一点就行了  差一点
A little more, that's it.
这不就没事了吗？
All done!
不要作弄他
Don't tease him.
他真好玩
That was fun.
你只会使诈！
You rascal!
-生气了？  -这么容易生气？
-Angry already? -You get angry so easily?
根本就不是男人
That's not manly of you.
真的生气了？
You're really angry?
我怎么会生气呢？
Not me!
伯父  我最爱玩了  有什么好生气的？
l like fun. Why are you angry?
你们又想做什么？
What are you up to?
真的不生气？
Not angry?
哪会生气呢？
Why would I be angry?
好恶心！
It's gross!
这么舒服  哪会生气呢？
It's so comfy, why get angry?
你也很爱玩吧？
-Don't you like some fun?
当然了
-Certainly.
大鸡蛋
An egg!
干什么？
What for?
你玩的话  我会生气的
Stop that!
我怎么会生气呢？
l am not angry, not at all.
-不会生气  -玩疯一点
Have some more fun!
不准耍赖啊
Come on, you have to do it.
来吧
Come on.
玩玩而已
Just for fun.
开始
Go!
第二会合  快点
Second round. Be quick!
英
Ying!
好棒
Bravo.
爸爸  玩够了没有？
Dad, that's enough.
还没有人窒息  继续  快点
No one's suffocated yet. Carry on.
-糟了  -伯父
Oh, no. Sir.
爸爸
Dad!
不好意思  伯父
Sorry for that, sir.
-都是你的错  -伯父  对不起
-Look what you did! -I'm so sorry, sir.
-伯父不会生气的  -别生气啊
He won't get angry.
-没问题的  伯父  -他不会生气吧？
It's okay.
-人中这么宽  心胸一定也很广阔  -不生气  没问题
His philtrum is so wide, that means he's open-minded.
-你说心胸广阔是吧？  -伯父  我帮你抹干净
Yes, he's not angry. It's okay, he's open-minded.
-来  干杯  再来喝  -干杯
-Come, bottoms up! -Bottoms up!
干杯
Bottoms up!
-干完它  我想睡了  -我送  你回家  回家去
-Ying, let me send you home. -I want to go to sleep.
晚安
-Goodnight. -Goodnight.
-阿英  -走了
-Ying... -Go away.
你们真没用  喝完它
You people are useless. Have more.
再见
Bye
阿英去了哪里？
Where is Ying?
-再见  -不喝了
Hey.
-走吧  -伯父  我们先走了
Sir, we are leaving.
门口不在那边
The main door is not there,
-这边  -你真是的
it's this way.
这边
This way.
伯父  再见
Bye, sir.
急
-l need the toilet.
厕所
l need the toilet. -Bye.
-好急  -厕所在哪里？
-Where's the restroom? -I'm in a hurry!
忍着
Hang on,
先按电梯按钮吧
press the button.
按错了  你按到上楼了
Wrong button!
怎么这么久？
What's taking it so long?
让我把电梯门打开就行了
Just open the door.
你先吧
You first.
你先上吧
After you.
礼让有奖吗？走吧
No prizes for politeness.
怎么会有人把衣服挂在电梯里边？
Why are there clothes in the elevator?
电梯就不能挂衣服吗？
Who doesn't hang clothes in elevators?
神经病
Are you nuts?
电梯怎么这么小？
-This elevator is so small!
好热啊
-It really hot!
难怪别人把衣服脱了挂这里
So people hang their clothes here.
为什么只挂衣服不挂裤子？
But there are only shirts here. Where are the pants?
到了吗？
Are we there?
推门吧  傻瓜
Push, stupid!
-到了  -到了哪里？
We're here. Where are we?
到了浅水湾
At Repulse Bay.
加勒比海的美人鱼
The Caribbean Sea!
在哪里啊？
Mermaid!
那边
Over there!
游泳过去吧
Let's swim there.
我蝶式
Butterfly stroke!
Butterfly stroke.
我自由式  要追过你
I'm freestyling, I'm coming!
我不会游的  给我救生圈  救生圈
Help, I can't swim! Give me a lifesaver or something!
我要救生圈
I want a lifesaver!
-干什么？  -什么事？
What the hell's going on here?
我的衣服呢？
My clothes?
-压死我了  -在这里
-It almost killed me.
阿英  什么事？
-Ying, what's the matter?
爸爸  我没事
Nothing, Dad,
我做恶梦而已
l had a bad dream!
做噩梦？
-Bad dream?
做恶梦？
-A bad dream?
-难道我们…  -走开！
-Did we... -Go!
不是吧？
It can't be!
-阿英  你告诉我  -走开！
-Tell me what happened. -Go!
-阿英  真的没事？  -告诉我究竟发生了什么事
-Are you all right? -Go away! Please go away!
-说吧  -快点走开！
Go!
怎么办？
What should we do?
我们会回来找你的
We will come back for you.
-阿英  你别哭了  -走开！
Ying, don't cry.
-我们一定会回来的  -是的
-We will be back. -Yes.
虾饺、烧卖
Hargou, Xiumai
要几笼？
How many?
昨晚是谁借酒行凶？快承认了
Who took advantage of her? Admit it!
昨晚的事与我无关
l had no part in anything last right.
我不知道睡得多熟  被人压着都不会醒
l slept so sound, nothing could wake me.
不会是我吧？
Can't be me.
阿英是我最倾心的人
l adore her so much.
我怎么会乱来呢？
l wouldn't do anything indecent.
那就是说究竟有没有发生过都不知道
We don't even know whether anything happened.
不可能啊
No way
不是你吧？
-It's not you?
当然不是我
-Of course not.
那又不是你？
It's not you?
那一定是我了  现在阿英已经是我的人
Then, it must be me. Now that Ying is mine, that means
朋友妻  不可欺
you don't go after your friend's wife!
你们以后对她不要再存有非分之想了
You two should not even fancy her.
对不起  我先走  这顿我请客
Excuse me. I'll pay for this meal.
我现在记清楚了
Now l remember.
昨晚我跟美人鱼聊天的时候
Last night I had a chat with the mermaid,
不知道有多开心呢
and boy we had such a great time.
我想应该就是我了
l think it was me.
-好了  -你别发梦了
-Okay. l admit.
我承认  是我做的
It was me. -Okay.
我真的不想说  可是我实在忍不住了
l don't want to say it, but now l won't hold back.
你们看看  我浑身都黏黏的
Look, my whole body is sticky.
-战绩尚在  证据充足  -只有你有吗？
-It's proof that I did it. -You don't say.
你看我  我也一裤子都是啊
Look at my stained pants!
一定是我！
It must have been me.
等等
Wait.
你看看  我整个头都是
Look here! It's all over my head.
乱讲  整个头都…
You've all admitted it. Hey.
你们现在抢着承认  那只会构成轮奸的罪名而已
Then it was gang rape!
-什么？轮奸也说得出口？  -搞什么啊？
What? Did he say gang rape?
真是金玉其外  败絮其中
These young people don't have any shame!
（大上海理发）
SHANGHAI BARBER SHOP
你好  开心仔
-Hi, Happy! -Hi.
喂  里边请
Please, go in.
阿英
Ying,
英  我想…
l want to...
天啊  我从没对女孩子这么真心
Heavens. I've never been so sincere to a girl,
现在害得我多么痛心
and now I'm so heartbroken.
阿英联络我们
Ying is paging us.
其实我根本不想再见到你们
Actually, l didn't want to see you again.
不过我最近觉得身体有点异怪
But I feel strange lately.
拿去验一下
Take this for a test,
有什么结果
and tell me the results.
尽快告诉我
As soon as you know.
-阿英  -阿英
-Ying. -Ying.
这瓶是什么东西？
What is this?
香水
Perfume.
-香水？  -试试看就知道了
-Perfume? -Try it.
味道好浓郁
It's so strong.
是尿  还玩？拿去化验用的
It's urine for the test.
怎么不早说？
Why didn't you say so?
-傻小子  -走吧
Let's go.
一小瓶  又不是一大桶
This is a bottle, not a barrel.
要三个人抬着去吗？
It doesn't take three to carry.
你明天拿去吧
You do it tomorrow.
又是我？
Me again?
不过为了阿英  丢脸一次也行
But I would do anything for Ying.
如果验出来这瓶是啤酒
If the test verifies this is draft beer.
那就真的是老天保佑了
I can just drink it.
去厕所小便吧
Go take your samples at the toilet. INQUIRY
什么事？
Can l help you?
验尿
Urine test.
放在盘子上
Put it on the tray.
（纪浩仁  验孕）
KEI HO YAN PREGNANCY TEST
这么巧？验什么？
What a coincidence! What's wrong with you?
是啊
Oh, yes.
小不出便所以来验一下
l can't urinate.
给点面子吧
With due respect, sir.
怎么？不是染病吧？
So is it VD?
不是  验一下尿有没有渣滓而已
No! To see if there is a precipitant in the urine.
伯父  你来这验什么？
What are you testing for?
糖尿  老毛病
Chronic diabetes, what else.
我帮你吧
Allow me.
你先坐一下
Have a seat.
（纪浩仁  验孕  祝大松  糖尿）
CHUK TAI CHUNG DIABETES
喂  龙眼仔
Big Eye,
你到底验什么？这么紧张？
what's the test for? Why so tense?
不知道  验出来是什么就是什么吧
l don't know. Whatever will be, will be.
用不着那么紧张吧？
Why so scared?
为你紧张而已
I'm scared for you.
-纪浩仁！  -有！
-Kei Ho Yan! -Yes!
纪浩仁有糖尿
You have diabetes.
有糖尿
Diabetes.
放心吧  严不严重？
Be calm. Is it serious?
严不严重？
Is it serious?
问医生吧
Ask a doctor.
问医生
You ask a doctor.
好吧  那就问医生吧
Right. Go and see a doctor.
-祝大松  -怎么样？
-Chuk Tai Chung. -What's the result?
关你什么事？
Why so nosy?
恭喜你  祝先生
Congratulations.
恭喜？
Congratulations?
糟了
Oh, no.
糟什么？他恭喜我  那就是说…
-What oh, no? He said congratulations.
你有了
-It's positive!
有了  你还恭喜我？
Positive and you congratulate me?
-让我看看  -老先生  以后就小心点吧
Be more careful from now on.
什么小心？我这种年纪还要小心？
Careful? At my age?
我才不管  肥的我也吃  瘦的我也吃
l don't care. Fat or skinny, I'll just eat.
总之能吃的  我就照吃了
I'll take so far as I've got the urge.
伯父  算了
Sir, leave it.
都不知道这间化验所的  化验结果准确的吗？
This lab may not be reliable.
去别间看看
Go elsewhere.
验孕
Pregnancy test?
又验孕？
Again!
恭喜人有糖尿病？这太离谱了
Congratulations on getting diabetes? Are they nuts?
伯父  你先看一下报纸
Sir, check out these ads.
看看有没有治糖尿病的  你先找找看
We could find a cure for your
-怎么样？验到什么？  -尿里有糖
diabetes among them.
喂？你喝过？
Did  you  drink  Ying's  urine？
Did you drink Ying's urine?
-阿英的尿都要喝？你这死小子  -对啊
You bastard.
说什么？我的阿英？
What? My Ying?
你自己都不知道是谁经手？
How come you don't know?
让我出去问他们
I'll question them.
喂  你们三个混蛋  到底是谁做的？
Who among you three did it?
最后一次  到底是谁？
-For the last time, who did it?
-说！  -快说！
-Answer now!
岂有此理  用刑！
Outrageous! Torture them!
我不想这件事成为轮奸丑闻
l don't want a gang rape scandal.
你肯指出是谁做的  你就可以平平安安
If you inform me of the culprit, we will set you off.
要不然的话  我就戳破你的两个耳膜
If not, I'll break your eardrums.
伯父  那怎么选？
How can I choose, sir?
那是说不是戳别人后背爆料  就得戳耳朵吗？
If I don't point out who did it, you will break my eardrums.
你想清楚  究竟是谁？
That's right! Who did it?
你自己？
You did it?
-有没有？  -有没有？
-Did you do it? -Yes or no?
去死吧！
Go to hell!
-怎样？  -先坐下
-How is it? -Sit down!
-先坐下  怎么了？  -到底怎么回事？
How is it?
-喂  怎么了？  -说吧
-How is it? -Tell us.
我耳朵聋了
l am deaf!
-还聋了？  -聋了？
-You're deaf? -You're deaf?
-是啊  -不会吧？
Are you sure?
喂  他们怎样虐待你？
How did he torture you?
你听到吗？
Can you hear?
我听不到
l can't!
-我听不到  -听不到？
-You can't hear us?
千万不要承认
-Never admit guilt!
他心狠手辣
He is ruthless.
怎么办？等一下就轮到我们了
Now what? Our turn will come.
布甸  进来
Puddin, come in.
-什么事啊？怎么了？  -我？
-What's it? Who is it? -Me!
伯母叫你
Ying's mom is calling you.
-你先吧  -是你
-You first. -You!
你先吧
No, you first.
朋友一场  你听我说吧
My friend, listen to me.
千万不要承认  知道吗？
Don't ever plead guilty. Get me?
喂  你听到吗？
Can you hear me?
什么？谁？
What? Who?
到底有没有做？说！
-Did you do it? Talk!
有没有？
-Did you?
说啊！
Talk!
去死吧！
Go to hell!
伯父  你真的这么残忍？
Why do you have to be so cruel?
你更残忍
You're crueler.
现在你要戳他们后背爆料  还是要我戳穿你的耳膜？
What's it going to be, information or eardrum?
最好是两样都不要
I would rather not choose.
有没有做过？
Did you do it?
有没有？
Did you?
承不承认？
Are you going to admit?
谢谢伯父不戳我
Thanks for not breaking my eardrum.
我不戳你耳膜  我要打你！
I'm not breaking your eardrums, I'll smack you!
别以为就这样而已
That will teach you.
出去！走！
Now, get out.
岂有此理  竟然这样作弄我们？
They've really made fools out of us. Hey.
伯父他放过我了
Ying's dad spared me.
说什么？
What?
放心吧
Relax.
我明天会去聋哑学校
Tomorrow I'll enroll you
帮你两个报名的
in the school for deaf and dumb.
放屁就走开一点啊
Your fart smells terrible!
放屁这么大声有奖吗？
And it's so loud!
你这两个死小子敢耍我？
You two played with me!
-等等！  -有什么理由  你自己都不知道？
How come you know nothing?
-上海佬  你想逼死女儿吗？  -我不管
-Mr. Shanghai, leave her alone! -I don't care,
把这个野种给打掉！
I want it aborted!
-别这样！  -别这样！
-Don't! -Don't!
我不会打掉
No,
l won't do it!
-别这样！  -你们这班畜牲！
Please, don't!
-我砍死你！  -别这样！
You bitch, I'll hack you to pieces.
-妈！  -不打掉胎儿  我就砍死你！
Now, you abort it or die!
-阿英  你快点走吧  快点！  -走吧！
-Ying, run away! Quick! -Hurry, come along with us.
-伯母  你殿后！  -不要走  回来！
Don't you run away!
我要告你们这些混蛋轮奸！
I'm going to report you for gang rape,
把屁股洗干净去坐牢吧！
so prepare to get your asses in jail!
-快走！  -回来！
Come back!
神经病  你想女儿登上头条吗？
You want her to be the newspaper headline?
-给我进房去！  -回来！
Get in your room!
快点
Quick.
-阿英  -喂
-Ying! -Hey!
-计程车  -计程车
Taxi!
追前面的计程车  快点！
Follow that taxi. Quick!
-喂  停车！我们还没有上车！  -喂！停车！
Hey, stop! We haven't gotten in!
-加油  大哥  -大哥啊
Step on it!
踩油门到底
Driver! Go faster!
-拜托你  -快点  尽快追到她
-Catch up with that taxi. -Please...
-拜托开快一点  -行了
-Come on, faster. -All right.
-就是前面那一辆  -会不会甩开我们？
Yes, it is that taxi in front.
追他
After it!
-快超他的车  -踩油门！
-Overtake it!
-干什么不去？走吧！  -快点！
-Why don't you go?
-干什么？  -干什么？
What's wrong?
-为什么停下来？  -为什么停车？
-Why did you stop? -Why did you stop?
大哥们  红灯了
It's the red light.
我已经被扣了11分
My license is 11 points off.
你想我被吊销执照吗？
Do you want my license to be suspended?
要扣分就扣他的  罚钱就罚我的
We are willing to pay for any penalty.
是的  司机大哥  如果你追到他
Yes. If you could catch up,
-我们就多加100元给你  麻烦你开车  -好！
I'll give you an extra 100 dollars.
好  执照是你的？是我的
-The license is mine, not yours. -Sure.
-拜托你  -好吧
-Please! -Please.
用点脑吧
Okay. Use your brain.
小鸟呼叫大象
Birdy calling Elephant.
小鸟  什么事？快说
What is it, Birdy?
我的车上有三个客人
Three passengers
你开慢一点  等等他们
here request you
你告诉他  我们要追我们胎儿的妈妈
Tell him, we want our baby's mother.
-叫他帮帮忙  -快点啊
So could you help us?
他们要找胎儿的妈妈
They want their baby's mother.
帮帮忙吧
Could you help them?
-麻烦你了  -麻烦你了
Thanks.
喂？她摇头
She shakes her head.
怎样？
How did it go?
她摇头
She shook her head.
你快点告诉她
Tell her this.
你说：“阿英  那晚的事  我们不是有心的”
Ying, we didn't do it on purpose that night.
-对啊  -对啊
Right....
阿英
Ying,
那天晚上的事
he said they didn't do
他说不是有心的
it on purpose that night.
你告诉她
Tell her I love her
“我爱她  爱到海枯石烂”
till heavens rot.
他爱…
He loves
爱到海…
you till...
枯…枯烂
vens... rot.
喂？什么枯烂？
What? "Vens rot"?
喂  小姐  这个枯枯烂  应该好不到哪里去
Miss, this one with rotten organs
捡到了只会让你一直哭  淘汰他吧
must be a rascal. Give him up.
喂  那个枯枯烂闭嘴  下一个
The rotten organs guy, shut up! Next!
替我告诉她：“我赖布甸为了她
Tell her that l, Puddin Lai,
我戒烟  不赌
promise to stop smoking, gambling,
赚钱不用  来养老婆”
and splurging to care for my wife!
这个说要戒烟不赌
He said, he would smoke... gamble...
赚钱不用来养老婆
splurge... no care for his wife!
这个不要也罢
This one is rotten too.
戒烟戒不到
Unwilling to give up smoking.
这么快就想好以后赚钱不用养老婆
And what good husband splurges money?
淘汰他
Give him up.
-淘汰他！  -下一个！
Next one!
让我来跟她说  阿英！
Let me talk! Ying.
该我了  不要抢
Hey, it's my turn.
阿英
Ying.
我不太会说话  不过…
l am not a good speaker,
我觉得你真的好傻
I think you're so stupid!
一个女人究竟最需要的是什么？
What does a woman need?
就是一个一生一世都这么爱她的男人
A man who loves her for life.
你现在还有三个  那你还想怎样？
Now, there are three men who do.
你冷静点想想
Calm down and think about it.
你现在一个人跑了出来
Now you're alone,
又没地方住  又没人照顾你
homeless, uncared for.
不如让我们帮你找个好的地方给你住
Let us find you a somewhere nice to stay
等胎儿出生
until you give birth.
到时候验出孩子是谁的
Once they verify who the father is,
我们就可以照顾你俩母子一生一世了
one of us will care for you for life.
拿来
Let me.
大象  拜托你就靠边停
Elephant, stop your car.
让他们见见面吧
Let them meet.
靠边停等那三个混账？
Wait for the three rascals?
你真是疯了  呆子！
You must be out of your mind.
不会开车  就别去学人开计程车
Not knowing how to drive, then don't be a driver.
喂！不要这样！
Oh, no!
这么好的男人
The three are
你都不珍惜
really nice guys.
算你们走运
You are in luck.
管它吊销执照
To hell with my driver's license!
好
Bravo!
喂  我要下车
I want to get down.
你想都别想
No way!
为了你的幸福  我不会让他们追到你的
For your future's sake, l won't let them get you.
我要下车！
Hey! Let me out!
-影子都见不到  -对啊
-I can't find them! -Yes.
-那怎么办？  -那怎么办？
-What can we do? -What can we do?
死大象、臭大象  报你的位置来
Elephant, tell me your position!
看…看我追不追到你
l can overtake you.
你问的时候  就在太子道头
l was in Prince Road when you asked.
现在在太子道尾  正在上龙翔道
Now, l am off to Lung Cheong Road.
追吧
Try and get me!
你想怎样？我要下车！
What do you want? Let me out!
打我的结局也是一样
Let them hit me.
我不会让那些混账追到你的
l won't allow them to catch you.
救命
Help!
真是王八蛋  来我的摊位捣乱
I won't let those bastards get in our way!
是哪个王八蛋？给我滚出来
Come out, you bastards!
出来
Come out!
阿英  你不要走  阿英
Ying, don't go away!
喂  王八蛋  醒醒
Get up, you bastard!
喂  醒醒吧
Get up.
阿英  你没事吧？
Ying, are you all right?
-阿英  你没事吧？  -有事吗？
-Are you all right? -Are you all right?
阿英  原来你这么漂亮
Ying, you are really gorgeous!
你们三个有眼光
You guys were pretty great.
我被吊销执照也是值得的
It was worth risking my license.
你别乱说啊
-Shut up! -Shut up!
大象
Elephant.
-大象  喂！  -阿英
-Ying... -Elephant, get up.
-他也算是活该  -你也有今天的下场吧
-Serves him right! -All covered in shit.
-阿英  -阿英  刚才在车子里说的话
Ying, what we just said in the taxi,
你的想法如何？
do you agree?
-阿英  我们是真心的  -是的
-We do mean it. -Yes!
-是的  -阿英  怎么办？
Are you okay with it, Ying?
好啊！
Wow! Great!
这地方是小了一点
This place is a bit small.
不过一个人住是够的  对吗？
But, for one person, l hope it is okay, right?
是的
Yes.
阿英  你什么都别想
Ying, forget anything else.
只要专心生孩子就行了
Just concentrate on baby-making.
你把阿英当什么？怎么生？
What do you take her for? How to make babies?
跟谁生？
With whom?
阿…阿英  我看了这房子
Ying, l studied this place,
应该跑不掉了
the feng shui here is pretty good.
正所谓：“家住富贵屋
This home will bring you riches,
一生衣食足  儿孙生满屋”
food, clothing, and many children.
挺可爱吧？
Cute, isn't it?
小心点
Be careful.
干什么？
What is it?
这次真是令人火冒三丈
You really pissed me off this time.
-胎教而已  -胎教吗？
-It's just prenatal education. -Prenatal education?
你不是也想生一个可爱的孩子吗？
Don't you like to have a cute baby?
这种畸型还叫可爱的孩子吗？
You call this thing a cute baby?
这样的小宝贝  你真是丢人现眼
I call it a freak!
-切掉它更好  -你真是好可爱
You are cute?
有飞机
It's just the plane.
你们三个这样
Look at you.
叫我怎么熬过这段日子？
l can't pass the days in peace.
你这个臭小子！
You are...
好兄弟
Guys!
-好到令人流泪  -是
Till death do us part!
简直是难分难舍
Nothing can tear us apart!
（当值太监  赖布甸）
EUNUCH ON DUTY PUDDIN LAI
妹爱哥情重
They are a
哥爱妹丰姿
lovely couple
为了心头愿  连理结双枝
Who want to stay together forever
只为一水隔天涯
But they have to be separated
任凭各位吃尽山珍海味
No exotic delicacy in this world
我打赌你们没吃过  这么好吃的西芹鸡丁
could stand up to a decent dish of celery with chicken.
这些是西芹鸡丁？
ls this celery?
当然
Of course. Here,
你尝尝看就知道  阿英
try some, Ying.
芹菜是要枝不要叶的
For celery, we eat the stem, not the leaves.
差劲
Shame on you!
恶劣
You lost face!
不是吧？
Oh, boy.
你看看  鲜艳翠绿
Look at how lush it is.
一口就想吃掉它
It makes your mouth water.
好东西都是留着最后才吃的
Should we save the best for last?
阿英
Ying,
给你吃
here. Have some.
吃块排骨吧
Have a spare rib.
所以都说你们不会分辨好东西
You guys don't know nuts about delicacies.
好东西贵精不贵多  一口就够了  饱了
Even for the best things, just a little is enough to fill your tummy.
既然是阿英夹给我的  那就吃吧
And since Ying gave it to me, I'll take it.
开心
Happy.
大家开心
Everybody's happy!
（当值太监  纪浩仁）
EUNUCH ON DUTY BIG EYE
盐腌
I've got to marinate it.
菜下锅
Vegetables in.
全焦了
It's all scorched!
少吃就能尝到多滋味
The less you take, the better it tastes. Where is it?
-这什么东西？  -这什么东西？
-What is this? -What is this?
鱼
A fish!
-鱼？  -可以敲出声音的？
It's hard as a rock.
是不是木鱼？
Is it petrified?
-新鲜的  -怎么这样的？
It's fresh.
里面还可以吃的
And it's edible.
阿英都说可以吃了
See, Ying says it is edible.
怎么？还不吃？
What? Won't you eat?
阿英都说能吃  那你就吃吧
Ying tells us to eat, so go ahead.
狗屎都要吃的
I would still eat it even if it's dog shit.
不要吃了
Don't,
鱼受到污染了
it is polluted.
现在的海水处处都受污染
Nowadays, sea water everywhere is polluted.
哪怕得了这么多？我偏要吃
So what's the point of worrying?
都说不要吃了  吃菜吧
Don't eat it. Have some vegetables.
这鱼有什么问题？说吧
Is something wrong with the fish? Tell me!
你真是聪明  全都被你猜中了
Bingo, that's the correct answer!
-你这臭小子  -你真是贱人  看着我吃还不哼声
You didn't stop me when you see me eat it!
什么？都是你自己说的
You raised the issue yourself, okay?
狗屎都要吃的  是吗？
Even dog shit is good.
阿英  对吧？
Right, Ying?
（当值太监  陈开心）
EUNUCH ON DUTY HAPPY
吃到你揉肚子
Gourmet's delight!
豆腐皮猪肚汤
Pig's belly
-滋养补肾  越喝越美  -试试看吧
with bean curd soup is good for your skin.
-味道不错  -不错吧？
-Tastes good. -It does?
不要人拼一锅汤  你拼一条命
But don't gobble it up.
苦的
It's bitter!
涩的
It's sour!
我才不管
For goodness sake,
别浪费它
don't waste it!
猪脑跟人脑的分别
Do you know the difference between smart and stupid?
就是猪脑弄芹菜给人家吃
Stupid serves you celery leaves,
吃得人家呱呱叫
and it makes us vomit.
笑什么笑？
What's so funny?
人脑  就煲猪肚汤
While smart serves you pig's belly,
大家喝了
and it earns
揉肚子
our praise.
加菜哦？
Look what he added.
不仅要揉肚子  简直是要拉肚子
That will surely give him a stomachache!
阿英  那些加料汤  你千万别喝
Ying, don't touch that soup. Don't drink it.
阿英
Eat something else.
-吃梅菜吧  -这是半肥瘦的
Here's a pork shoulder.
阿英  什么事？
Ying,
我是不是做错事了？
did l do something wrong?
对不起  我这人又笨
Sorry, I'm too stupid
又不会照顾你
to take care of you.
不是
No,
我想家
I miss my family!
那你也不用难过
Don't be sad.
等孩子生下来了
When the baby is born,
那就可以一家团聚了
we will happily meet them again.
你真好
You are so kind.
是？是不是三个之中最好？
Am I the kindest of all three?
你们三个…
All three of you...
不可以这样
No, don't!
还不知道谁是爸爸
We still don't know who the father is.
不可以这样
So please.
好  对不起
Okay. I'm sorry.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
糟了  我没有纸巾
Oh, no. I didn't bring tissue paper!
纸巾？有
l have some.
我有
Yes. l...
来吧
Here...
还好吗？
Are you all right?
对不起  把你衣服弄脏了
Sorry, l ruined your shirt.
我回去帮你洗
I'll clean it for you.
没关系
It's all right.
你吐吧
Come on,
用力
let it out.
有机会！
喂！等等
Wait!
等等
吐不出来
No more.
那我不是什么都没有？
Then, l get nothing?
-没关系的  你继续吐  吐吧  -我就有呢
It's okay. If you want to throw up, just do it.
谢谢
Thank you.
衣服还能要吗？
Can l keep the clothes now?
就快可以生了  小心点
Be careful.
-有没有搞错？这三个男人来干啥？  -对啊
Are you kidding me? Why do these three stooges show up like this?
第一次来看医生吗？
-Is this your first time here?
是的
-Yes.
孩子的爸爸贵姓？
What's the father's name?
-X先生  -X先生？
-Mr. X. -Mr. X?
那X就X吧
Mr. X, whatever.
小姐
Miss,
小姐  你爸爸在这里
your father is here!
爸爸
Dad.
-伯父  -伯父
-Sir! -Sir!
-爸爸  -伯父
-Dad. -Sir.
小姐  两个月不见  你去了哪里？
We haven't seen you for two months. Where have you been?
去调景岭留学了
They must have been to boarding school.
去调景岭留学？
Boarding school?
你
You three,
过来
come with me.
走吧
come
进来
Get in.
这里这么晒  小姐  我们不如去另一边吧
It's hot out here. We better get in the shade.
-伯父  -伯父
-Hello, sir! -Hello, sir!
伯父  你把我们都叫进来
Sir, did you call us
不是想打999报警吧？
just so you can hand us to the cops?
你们这些混蛋别吵
You bastards shut up!
这件事不会这么就算数
We're not done with this yet.
我只是不想家丑外传
l don't want a scandal.
你们小心点  免得被我的伙计知道
Be careful! Don't let him find out.
笑  大家要笑
You all better chuckle.
伯父  你想怎么样？
Sir, what are you up to?
现在阿英呢  不肯去堕胎
Now, Ying refused to abort it.
意思就是要选你们其中一位
That means she has to marry one of you.
你们谁要娶她
The lucky man has to
就要美金五十万
pay me half a million US dollars.
少一毛都不行
Not a cent less.
你爸爸好像变了
Your dad has changed.
-对啊  -跟他们三个有说有笑的
-He's so friendly to the three.
对了  大家都快是一家人了  打个特惠价行吗？
-Yes! We're all family, so could you give us an 80% discount?
你闭嘴
Shut up!
钞票是真的  感情是骗人的
Money is real, kinship is bullshit.
酒席  就要摆60桌
I want 60 tables at the wedding banquet
另外房子一栋
and one apartment,
很小而已  只要120平方米就够了
only 1,300 square feet is fine.
不准苦笑
Make it look like
开心点
we're having a good time.
真好笑
That was really funny.
爸爸
Dad!
爸爸  我们是不是回家？
Dad, can we go home now?
乖女儿  你怎么能回家呢？
Ying, you can't go home.
你一天大过一天
You have so much homework to do,
还有七个月就毕业了
and you're graduating in seven months.
你用功一点熬过去吧
So you've got to work hard.
阿福  我们先回去
Fook, let's go home.
-岂有此理  -再见  伯父
Bye, sir.
有空再一起笑吧
Let's chuckle again next time.
五十万
We've got to pay half a million.
60桌
Sixty tables.
120平方米
And 1,300 square feet.
-要不要拼命？  -拼命
-Are you with me? -Count me in!
拼啊
Count me in!
阿英  我一定会为  你拼到底的
Ying, we will work hard for you.
别想这么多了  先送她回家吧
Enough chatter, let's take her home.
-走吧  -阿英  走吧
-Go, Ying. -Let's go.
一生都是命和运  半点不由人
It's all fated, you can't change it.
（赖布甸）
PUDDIN LAI FORTUNE TELLER
赖真人
Master Lai.
请坐
Sit please.
大叔的虎眼含威  如土生金
Sir, you have eyes as powerful as a tiger, and it's like a gold mine.
赖真人  你不认得我吗？
Master Lai, do you remember me?
司机大哥  认得
Oh, Mr. Driver!
你大难不死  必有后福
You escaped an accident, you're going to strike it rich.
让我再指点一下  包你飞黄腾达
Let me give you advice on how to make a big fortune.
真的吗？赖真人  我已当你是活神仙了
That is fine. l take you as a living god.
说得好
Good.
真人  你不是说不摆摊子的吗？
But, Master Lai, you told me you didn't have a workplace.
我家有贤妻幼儿  重出江湖
But l have a wife and a child now.
闯荡一会而已  言归正传
Let's go back to you.
大叔印堂红日高升
-Your brow is like the glowing sun. -Yes?
-是吗？  -可惜有半点乌云
But there is a tinge of black cloud.
不要擦了  擦不掉的
You can't wipe it off that way.
我看最近事业有点不如意  是吗？
I believe that times are tough for you lately.
是的  真人  你真是灵验如神
Exactly! Master Lai, you're a living god.
-把手给我看看  -好
-Let me see your palm. -Sure.
努力点驾多几轮吧
You've been working so hard behind the wheel.
怎么样？
Yes!
给我另外一只手看看
Besides that...
买房子吧
You should buy some real estate!
赖真人  你真是世外高人
Master Lai, you're truly divine!
都是那些小人在抬价  不太顺利
I have a lot of competition recently.
想买哪里？
So what would you like to buy?
康乐大厦
Connaught Centre.
有眼光  商业单位是稳赚的
Good choice! Commercial unit, stable returns!
不是一个单位
Not just one unit,
是整栋
but the whole block!
我第一次看见大叔
The first time l saw you,
就知道你终非池中物了
l knew the sky is your limit.
我早说过你是富贵之相了  对吧？
You have a face of nobility.
我给你一些灵符吧  不过要记住
l give you a set of talismans. Remember.
一道贴胸口  一道贴床头
Put one on your chest, one on your bed,
一道贴床尾
one under the bed,
洗澡也千万不能弄湿
don't wet it even in the bath.
弄湿了就不灵  三天之后
When wet, it loses its power. Three days later,
要是谁还抬价  谁就死
whoever tries to compete with you will be wiped out.
-阿超  -是
-Chiu! -Yes!
拿五千元给真人
Five thousand dollars for Master Lai.
他是我秘书
He's my secretary.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢超哥
Thanks, Mr. Chiu.
大叔的相真是百年难得一见
It's not every day I see a face like that.
不如来个全裸观相吧？
Would you like me to read your face?
小仁  你缝腊肠还是缝西裤？
Ho Yan, are you making a pair of pants or a gunny sack?
对不起  我拆掉它再改
Sorry, I'll do it again.
你记得弄好  明天一早要交货的
Do it right, I need it by tomorrow morning.
-知道吗？  -我知道
-Got it? -Got it.
小仁  你怎么这么拼命？
Ho Yan, why are you working so hard?
存老婆本
I want to get married.
是这样吗？
Oh,
骗到女子上当了吗？
you want to pick up a girl?
不久后连孩子也会有了
Soon enough, you will get a child.
还有孩子？
Who knows,
那就是买大送小了
maybe you will have more than one child.
差不多
Who knows?
傻小子  你真的像水仙不开花那样
You know, you're like a black man in a black forest.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
那就是你装蒜
You're all in the dark.
怎么样？不错吧？
How's this? Is it good?
-外面付钱吧  谢谢  -谢谢
Thanks for coming.
小姐  不好意思  我们打烊了
Sorry, miss, we are closing.
-先帮我弄好吧  -老板
-Why not do my hair first? -Boss!
什么事？
Can I help you?
小姐  坐里边吧
Step in please.
老板  让我做完这个吧
Sir, let me do one more.
好吧
Okay.
谢谢  老板
Thank you, sir.
又拼命了
I'm going to toil again!
请坐
Sit please.
喂  开心仔  怎么这么拼命？
Happy, you're working hard?
没办法了  要养一家大小
I can't help it. l have to feed the family.
-少睡两个小时也没办法的啊  -真是服了你
-I don't mind losing two hours of sleep.
就这样吧  再见
-You're really something!
小姐  想怎么剪？
What cut would you like?
我想剪短一些
A bit shorter.
-开心仔！  -开心仔！
-Happy! -Happy!
你们好  亲爱的
Hi!
-为什么过来这里了？  -你怎么过来这里了？
So, you changed salons.
先亲一个
-Let me kiss you!
安静！
老板  我做完这些熟客  帮你锁门吧
Stop! Boss, three more jobs,
好的
please.
-我们会自便的  -开心仔  来吧
-We know what to do. -We know what to do.
坐下！
-Sit.
好的  开始
-Come on.
还有多久？
-How long do I have to wait?
快点过来先帮我剪吧
-Make mine first.
怎么你们全都无精打彩？
Why do you guys look so tired?
不是  我先天好
No. I'm fine.
我后天强
I'm doing good.
我心地善良
I got a heart of steel.
-我们精力过盛  简直想打架了  -我们精力过盛  简直想打架了
We're so pumped up, we feel like sparring! EUNUCH ON DUTY
我的毛巾
Where is my towel?
-是的  这里环境蛮不错的  -这里风景不错
-This place looks nice, doesn't it? -It does.
空气比较清新  是吗？
Yes, we can get some fresh air here.
-怎么了？  -阿英  怎么了？
-What's the matter? -Ying, are you all right?
让我来吧
Let me help you.
-他又踢我  -我儿子真是顽皮
-It's kicking me. -My child is so mischievous.
慢慢来
Slowly.
儿子啊儿子  你别顽皮
Be good, my little one.
过两个月  你就会出来为我们宣判命运
In two more months, you will come out and decide our fate.
放开你的手
Hands off!
到时就会有两个脆弱的心灵
And you're going to break the hearts
澈底地破碎
of two men by then.
你别担心
Don't worry,
我会送个强力万能胶给你
I'll give you some glue
把它黏起来
to mend those hearts.
黏你的死人头  你…
Better to mend your head!
其实你们三个都是好人
ln fact, all three of you are gentlemen.
又勤快
You're hardworking,
又负责任
responsible,
-还很有才干  -说得也是
and capable.
以后我嫁给你们其中一个
When l marry one of you,
不知道到那时候
will the three of
你们三个人还会是好朋友吗？
you still be good friends?
我们一向来都很听你的话
We've been together for so long.
一直都保持好朋友的关系
Aren't we good friends all along?
好  真好
Yes, we truly are.
好
Yes.
好你老母！
Up yours!
它老母只是母狗
-It's just a dog, okay?
-这样你也不放过？  -走吧
-Just ignore it.
-你还算是人吗？  -走吧
Can't you be a little humane?
阿英  你别怪他  他这个人就是这样
Ying, you know what he is like.
（何二姑  流产所）
AUNTIE HO'S MATERNITY HOME
上海佬  我好紧张
Old man, l am nervous.
你摸摸看  我手都凉了
My hands are freezing!
恭喜你抱孙子乐
Congratulations, you're going to have a grandchild.
这么紧张做什么？坐下来  老婆
Why so tense, sit down.
你们来了  爸爸、妈妈、干爹
You're here, Mom, Dad, godfather.
岳丈、岳母
My in-laws are here.
-爸爸  -别乱叫  现在听起来很好听吗？
Stop! I don't want to hear that.
我的孙子有三个爸爸？走
My grandchild doesn't have three fathers. Go!
快点走
Get lost!
是不是要我把你们砍成十几块？
Or else, I'll hack you to pieces
再拿去喂狗？
and feed you to the dogs.
算了
All right.
你们回去吧  先回去吧
Go home first!
回去吧
Go!
等一等
Wait!
把东西放下
Put those down.
走吧
Go now.
妈妈
Ma'am!
什么事？
What?
妈  这是我的血型报告
This is my blood type.
如果验出来儿子是我的
If it is proven that the baby is mine,
我会送个围嘴儿给你
I'll buy you a big present.
妈妈  如果是我的  我愿叩头奉茶
Ma'am. If it is mine, I'll kneel and serve you tea.
父子铁证在这里
-This is solid proof of my paternity.
-妈妈  -妈咪
-Ma'am!
还不走？在这里做大戏吗？
Stop fooling around already, go!
走吧
-Go away!
-走吧  -妈咪
-Ma'am.
走吧
-Go away!
两种  雄型和雌型的
Two. Male and female.
那这些是雄的还是雌的？
So which one is male and which one is female?
这些是…
It's all
英文
in English.
什么意思？
What does it say?
这次大爆冷  三个都是A型
This is odd, they are all type A!
天灵灵  地灵灵  坤干一对
Give me a sign!
必定是儿子
I'm sure it will be a boy.
我想也是
I think so too.
还不知道
It's uncertain.
喂  谢谢你们俩这么久以来  帮我照顾阿英
Thanks for taking care of Ying so far,
顺便帮我儿子取个名字吧
how about giving my child a name?
-你在做梦吗？  -你清醒点吧
-You're dreaming. -Have some wit.
叫赖布冧
How about Plum Lai.
冧核
Plum stone.
妈咪
Ma'am!
妈咪来了
She's here.
-是儿子还是女儿？  -妈咪
Is it a boy or girl.
妈咪  怎样？妈咪
What is it?
-妈咪  跟我长得一样是吧？  -怎样？
-Does it look like me? -Ma'am.
跟我的血型一样吗？
Of the same blood type?
妈咪  你说吧
Ma'am, tell us.
妈咪  你所吧  是儿子还是女儿？
Ma'am, tell us, please. Is it a boy or a girl?
生了个儿子
It's a boy.
-是儿子  好棒！  -都说了吧？我一早都说是儿子了
-Wow, Great. l knew it! -It's a boy!
那就是杂种  大松把他卖了给干爹
But he's an illegitimate son. Dad sold him to his godfather.
-卖掉了我儿子？  -为什么要卖了他？
-He sold my son? -He sold my son?
明早还要带他回加拿大
And he's taking him to Canada tomorrow.
得要他还回来啊
Hey, give him back to me!
干爹是青山的土皇帝  又凶又有钱
They don't call him godfather for nothing. He's rich and powerful!
-你们没希望的  -妈咪
-Don't even think of taking that boy! -Ma'am!
走开！
Move it!
-妈咪  -妈咪
-Ma'am! -Ma'am!
你说怎么办？
What now?
我看是我们该团结拼一拼的时候了
We must stick together for once.
好吧
Okay.
-团结  -团结
-Let's unite! -Let's unite!
-呆子  -呆子
Dumbass.
来吧
Come on.
儿子  吃奶奶  你在哪里？
Kid, I got you some milk. Where are you?
这方位大吉大利  不会碰钉子的
This is an auspicious direction, I'm sure of it.
-可是会碰到墙  -是啊
-But it's a wall. -Yes.
他真是智障  可以用爬的啊
Enough talk, let's climb.
-是啊  -行了
-Right. -Yes. Go on.
吃得多  拉得多  整天烦老哥  走吧！
You've caused so much trouble today.
快点！走快点！
Bad dog, now go out!
走快些吧
Run quickly.
儿子  吃奶奶  回答爸爸吧
Where are you, son? Daddy's here.
-大眼仔  -儿子啊
-Big eye boy.
是大鼻仔
-Big nose boy.
喂  这边是西北方
This way's northwest.
-来吧  -去吧
Let's go.
大眼仔
Big eye boy.
-大眼仔  -大鼻仔
-Big eye boy. -Big nose boy.
-上！  -喂！
-I'm coming! -Hey.
你以为你是超人吗？说上就上？
You think you can fly up there?
-找方法吧  -也对
Can't you find a path first?
东南？
Southeast?
没道理啊
That's weird.
都说我不会错的
l was right!
小布甸  我来了
Little Puddin, here l come.
-宝贝乖  宝贝听话  -多得很想讲也讲不了
Good baby, nice baby.
-宝贝明天要坐飞机了  -人人朝着那方向  心中带着笑
You're going to fly tomorrow, so you better be good.
-宝贝乖啊  -浮浮沉沉天空里热烈地呼叫
-Be good. -The sun is smiling bright
兴奋事情  嘻嘻哈开心到不得了
Everyone is incredibly happy!
灵感IQ称得上十分之高超
Inspiration and IQ are excellent
创作力量和幻想会吓你一跳
My originality And imagination may scare you
小云和小吉好重要
Both Wan and Gat are equally important
美梦如炸弹开心地…
You'll see me happily...
-天空朗日也偷笑  -天空朗日也偷笑
Smiling at the sky
-猪仔来了  -猪仔来了
"Here comes Mr. Piggy!"
天神村的早晨是特别美丽的
"It's a wonderful morning in Penguin Village."
谁知道  事情发生了
But something big is happening.
是啊  被四眼怪弄得乱七八糟
A four-eyed monster is causing trouble.
我不是有心的
I didn't do it on purpose!
开玩笑的  别太认真
I was kidding. Don't be so serious.
别这么八卦  早点睡吧
Don't be nosy. Go to bed.
我IQ博士快要死了
"I'm Dr. Slump, and I'm dying."
小吉来了！
"Gatchan is here!"
无厘头岛赐我力量！
"By the power of Grayskull!"
你去死吧
Stop it!
走吧
Run.
则卷千兵卫？
He-man?
回去吧  不然就惨了！
Go inside! You're making things worse!
博士  刚才打雷有没有电到你？
Dr. Slump, you were electrocuted?
当然有  差点被电晕
Of course, I nearly fainted. -"Boo-bee." -"Boo-bee."
什么事？
What's the matter?
山吹老师照镜子会照见你的  傻瓜
Ms. Yamabuki could see you in her mirror, you fool!
吃酸梅姜
When we eat pickled plum...
变超人
We will become Superman!
-飞吧  -好棒
-We're going to fly. -Yes!
超人  飞吧！
Superman, going up.
超人又碰钉子了
Superman, you crashed again.
超人  快回来吧
Superman, come back here.
你过来吧
This way,
来吧  快点！
quick.
喂！别冲进大雾  会迷路的！
Not that way, this way.
叫他回去睡觉吧  小吉
Get him to sleep first, Gatchan! "Boo-bee."
博士  超人睡觉了
Doctor, Superman is asleep.
你可以继续你的研究工作了
You may carry on with your research.
你快用人工呼吸救他  恶心也没办法了
Resuscitate him, even if it's gross!
电话响了
The phone is ringing.
喂？全部天神村的人都睡了  明天再打吧
The whole village is asleep now. Call back tomorrow.
真不识趣
What bad timing!
我来接电话吧
I'll take it.
都说睡觉了
Everyone's trying to sleep here!
怎么这么麻烦？
What a bother.
宝贝呢？
Where's the baby?
不是宝贝  是“补逼”
Not "baby," it's "boo-bee"!
超人醒了
Superman is awake!
我们可以继续玩了  玩吧
We can play again now. Come on. "Boo-bee."
还没睡吗？
Still awake?
我的儿子啊  别这样！
Is my sun...
你好  美女  等一等
Hi, pretty, hold on a minute.
亲一个
Want to kiss?
亲什么？
Kiss this!
让我来
Let me do it.
先克一克你
I've got to ward off some evil.
还有呢
There's more.
好可爱啊
So pretty!
-给我  -你才可爱
-Pass to me. -You're the pretty one!
别跑
Stop!
放手
Let go!
-把儿子还给我  -谢谢
-Give me back my son! -Thank you!
儿子！
My son!
-我看我不行了  你帮我抚养成人吧  -给我！
l am done for. Take care of my son.
做什么？
What?
-把他们都抓起来  -我踩！
Arrest them all.
儿子！
Son!
还给我
Give it back!
还给我啊！
-儿子  -儿子
-Son! -Son!
-阿强  -布甸仔！
-Keung! Rush the baby to the hospital.
-什么事？  -阿强  快点开车送孩子到医院
-What is it?
-快点  -快点
-Quick. -Quick.
快点去医院啊！快去！
Go to the hospital!
护士小姐  什么情况？
Miss...
阿英  快点来浸会医院
Ying, come quickly to Baptist Hospital.
来了再说  快点
I'll tell you everything later. Hurry!
如果我儿子有什么三长两短  你们…
-If anything happens to my son,
-你儿子？  -你儿子？
you-- -Your son?
那是我的亲生骨肉
He is my flesh and blood.
对啊
Yes
那是我买回来的
l bought him.
在律师楼签合约  现在就是我的合法骨肉
I signed it with my lawyer, so the kid is mine!
喂  你…
You...
你有钱就了不起吗？
You're rich, so what?
医生出来了
The doctor's here.
医生  怎样了？
How is it?
婴儿的脑受了严重震荡
The baby is suffering from a serious concussion.
要立刻替他做手术
We have to operate him at once.
谁是他爸爸？马上签名
Who's the father here? Please sign.
-我签  -我来
-I'll sign. -Allow me.
我才是合法爸爸
l am the legal father.
婴儿医好了也可能终身迟钝
Even if the baby survives, he will be mentally challenged.
是白痴啊？
If he's a retard,
他们才是亲生爸爸  快点签
then this is his real father! Now sign!
小白痴一个  口水一滴滴
My son's a retard now. What can I do?
-我签  -而且很有可能是植物人
-Let me sign. -He will probably be a vegetable child.
-买棵椰菜更好  -植物人？
-l would like a cabbage. -Vegetative.
让我来签
I'll sign.
儿子  爸爸妈妈一辈子  都会照顾你  养育你的
Dad and Mom will care for you and love you forever.
医生  麻烦你了
Here, doctor.
神经病  什么都要抢？
Why do you have to fight over everything?
你想清楚了吗？  你连自己过活都有问题
Have you thought it over? You can't care for yourself.
儿子…
-My son...
-死了？  -死了？
He's dead? -He's dead?
-儿子  -儿子
-Son!
妈妈！
-Ma'am!
洋娃娃
A doll!
如果是真的  哪有这么容易去我那里偷？
If it were real, we wouldn't have let you get away with it!
他们会放过你们吗？
You think they would let you in?
-还给你  -那现在我的儿子在哪里？
-Take it back. -Where is my son then?
-英  -儿子
-Ying! -Son!
儿子
Son!
乖
Good boy.
长得跟我一样
He looks just like me.
神经病
Are you nuts?
爸爸  大功告成  没我的事了
Sir, I've done my part now.
我回去工作了
I have to go back to work
要是被院长看到
before the chief finds out.
-会被开除的  -好
He would fire me!
-原来你串通来骗我  -竟然骗我们
So it's a prank on us.
不是骗  是我想出计划来试探你们
Not for fun. It's my plan to test you.
你们三个都这么疼阿英
You three love Ying the same,
而且你们三个人的血型全都是A型
and you all have the same blood type, type A.
畸型才对
Queer type!
-三个都是A？  -龙眼仔
-All type A? -Big Eye,
还是你最乖  你的心肠最好
you are the kindest,
你又最疼阿英  所以阿英嫁给你
so devoted to Ying. Marrying you,
我就最放心了
-make me feel secure. -Really?
-她要是不喜欢  我随时接手  -让我抱抱吧
-If you don't want, I'll take her anytime!
抱什么抱？闭嘴
-Really? Not so fast!
要是一天没有120平方米的  房子首期订金
Until I get that one thousand three hundred square foot apartment,
没有60桌酒席  没有五十万美金
sixty tables, and half a million dollars,
一个月只准见面一次
you can meet only once a month.
闭嘴  我说下个月就摆喜宴
Shut up! I'm going to wed her next month.
请多少桌都没关系
The number of tables doesn't matter.
岳母  真的吗？
Really, ma'am? Hey.
这么好的女婿  你还有什么不满的？
You got yourself a good son-in-law! What else do you want?
-没有  -跟我到那边去
-No! -Come with me.
-儿子  叫爸爸  -叫爸爸
-Call me daddy. -Say daddy.
临门一脚输了
Fate has
-爸爸爱死你了  -天意
brought them together.
这次你赢了  龙眼仔
You struck it big this time, Big Eye.
你们两个开心点
You two cheer up.
大家还是好朋友
You're still good friends.
-对吗？  -是  当然
Right! Of course.
儿子  这是大伯父  这是二伯父
This is Chan and this is Puddin.
看清楚他到底像谁
Who does
当然像我
he look like?
我跟阿英生的
We...
阿英  以后我生一大群龙眼仔好吗？
Ying, we're going to make us a squad of Big Eye boys.
你行吗？
Can you do it?
等着瞧
No problem.
好了
Done.
-帮你剪个新发型  -不要
-I want to cut your hair. -No!
还有你
Your turn.
-救命  -别走
-Help! -Don't run.
-爸爸  -别走啊
-Daddy! -Don't run!
-爸爸  -来吧
Daddy,
爸爸  哥哥想帮我剪头发
he wants to cut my hair again.
怎么整天欺负弟弟？
Don't bully your brother.
他都不肯让我剪
They won't let me cut.
上次你乱剪我的头发
The last time you cut my hair, you left a bald patch on me!
害我被同学笑了三个月
The whole school laughed at me for three months.
同学也有笑我
l am laughed at too.
笑你？笑你什么？
Laugh at you, why?
我鼻子大  眼又小  都不像你
My nose is big and my eyes are small, l don't look like you.
他们都说我像陈叔叔
They say l look like Chan.
别理他们怎么说  你是爸爸的乖儿子
Don't mind what people say, you're my dear son.
爸爸最疼你了
Daddy loves you the same.
-妈咪  -来吧  来公公这里
-Mommy. -Come on, Grandpa's here.
宝贝  快来婆婆这里
Young ones, come to Grandma.
-婆婆抱抱了  小心肝乖  -宝贝乖
-Let Grandma hold you. -Good girl.
来亲亲婆婆  来吧
Come, give Grandma a kiss.
阿英
Ying,
爸爸
Dad.
-咖啡  -乖
Coffee please.
爸爸  来  过来吧  阿英
Come here, Ying.
怎样？验到什么？
What's the test result?
你猜猜看
You guess.
还用验吗？我阿英是永不落空的
No need to test. Ying never disappoints you.
是吗？
Yeah?
我们又快要多一只乳猪仔了
We have another child!
妈咪万岁
Long live Mommy!
女婿
Ho Yan.
阿英
Ying
又快要帮你生第六个了
is having your sixth child.
你知不知道女人生小孩是很辛苦的？
Bearing a child is really tough, you know?
我知道  所以我向来都很疼阿英的
l know, that's why l love Ying so much.
是吗？应该的
You should.
爸爸  你也应该开心
Dad, you should be happy too.
120平方米  五十万  我全都办到了
The apartment, half a million, all delivered.
我很开心  我没说不开心
l am happy. Not complaining at all.
不过最好呢
But,
就是有艘大游艇
if there is a big yacht,
可以出海享受一下
-we can enjoy on the sea,
-是吗？  -大游艇？
right? -Big yacht.
没问题
No problem.
你买得起的啊
You can afford it.
爸爸明天就买艘大游艇  给大家好不好？
How about buying a big yacht?
-好棒  -好棒
-Good! -Bravo!
你真是最佳女婿
You're the best son-in-law.
谢谢爸爸
Thank you, Dad.
记得写我的名字
Put it in my name.
-又是你的吗？  -又是我啊
-Yours again? -Mine again.
剧终